<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Michael’s Blog Journal</title>
    <subtitle>A quiet place for thoughts, tech, and reflections.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-07-16T20:09:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Keep Trek Running</title>
        <published>2025-07-16T20:09:07-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-16T20:09:07-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/keep-trek-running/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/keep-trek-running/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/keep-trek-running/">&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;star_trek_constant_exploration.png&quot; alt=&quot;Futuristic starship gliding past a distant planet with nebula clouds in the background, symbolizing Star Trek&#x27;s enduring journey and its vision of an attainable future&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was just watching an old episode of &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Deep Space Nine&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I’ve always been into Star Trek, every series except &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: The Next Generation&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I’m not sure why, but I never fully got into that one. The others: &lt;em&gt;The Original Series&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Deep Space Nine&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Voyager&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Enterprise&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and all the movies (except the &lt;em&gt;Next Generation&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; ones), I loved and eagerly awaited. Whether it was a new film release or the next week’s episode, I was always excited. I never watched &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: The Animated Series&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; either, even though I own it on DVD.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Paramount+&#x2F;CBS introduced new series: &lt;em&gt;Discovery&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Picard&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Strange New Worlds&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Prodigy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Lower Decks&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I enjoyed those too, though I hated waiting a week between episodes. I think Netflix got it right: if a show isn’t airing on linear TV, just drop the whole season at once.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I even writing this post? Because I think they need to keep a Star Trek series running constantly. And if there’s no show currently airing, there should be a movie in development. The Star Trek universe is expansive enough to support both quality and quantity. There are fans who will keep these stories going. For me, Star Trek represents a future that feels more achievable than the world of Star Wars.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe we’re close to living in a Star Trek–inspired society technologically. Politically, we may resemble Star Wars more with wannabe emperors, kings, queens, and dictators everywhere or bubbling under the surface.  Still, I prefer the world of Star Trek, it’s more attainable in terms of its technology and processes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take Star Wars, for example. It’s supposed to be highly advanced, yet some aspects feel oddly underdeveloped. Star Trek isn’t perfect either, but its depiction of artificial intelligence seems closer to where we are today. I think we should take inspiration from how AI is portrayed in Star Trek. &quot;The Computer&quot; is always just a word away—accessible, helpful, and never intrusive or obstructive like some AI experiences today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#StarTrek #TV #SciFi #entertainment&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Capturing the Moon with My Seestar S30</title>
        <published>2025-07-06T13:15:00-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-06T13:15:00-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/zwo-seestar-s30-post/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/zwo-seestar-s30-post/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/zwo-seestar-s30-post/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted a telescope. Something I could use to take photos and videos of the night sky with my phone or camera. I recently came across a YouTube video about the Zwo Seestar S50, but since this is my first telescope, I decided to start with the more beginner-friendly &lt;strong&gt;S30&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and bought it for my birthday.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve owned it for a couple of months, but only recently started using it seriously. Here are some of the first photos I captured with it on &lt;strong&gt;July 4, 2025&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;seestars3007042025.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moon from Seestar S30&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;seestars3007042025(1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Detailed moon surface from Seestar S30&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These images were taken right from my front yard — I still can’t believe the clarity. Here’s one I took with my phone (Galaxy S24 Ultra, no zoom) while I was setting up the Seestar:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;moonfromphnes24ultranonzoom07042005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moon from phone with no zoom before telescope setup&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that evening, we heard fireworks going off in the distance. While the moon was the star of the night, I also caught this fun fireworks shot from our front yard. We were hearing more fireworks from our neighbors all around us than we were actually seeing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;fireworksathome07042025.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fireworks from home on July 4th&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m planning to set up a dedicated page in the future as I learn more about using the &lt;strong&gt;Seestar S30&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. I hope you enjoyed these photos as much as I enjoyed experimenting with the telescope. It’s truly amazing how it filters out light and zooms in on the moon with such detail.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;#astronomy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#telescopes&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#moon&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#personal&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Blogging My Way: Typora + Git + Cloudflare + Micro.blog</title>
        <published>2025-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/myfirstpost/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/myfirstpost/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/myfirstpost/">&lt;p&gt;This post serves two purposes. First, it marks the inaugural entry 🥳 on my new blogging system.
I&#x27;m using Typora ✍️ to write and save my posts locally in a folder. From there, I &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; them to my GitHub repo 🔁, which then deploys to Cloudflare Pages 🌐. Finally, the RSS feed is imported into Micro.blog 📰.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not as elegant as MarsEdit 💻—the polished Mac-only tool—but it works for now and lets me keep using Typora, which I really like.
I tried Obsidian 🧩, but it felt too complicated. The whole &quot;vaults&quot; system 🤯 didn’t click with me. Typora is just simple and clean ✅.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;#blogging&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#typora&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
