<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Michael’s Blog Journal</title>
    <subtitle>A quiet place for thoughts, tech, and reflections.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-10-25T00:33:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Two Pis, many plans, limited focus</title>
        <published>2025-10-25T00:33:41-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-10-25T00:33:41-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/lot-to-do/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/lot-to-do/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/lot-to-do/">&lt;figure class=&quot;captioned&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;electronics_researcher_working_on_circuit_board.png&quot;
       alt=&quot;A middle-aged man with a beard and glasses is deeply focused while working on an electronic circuit board in a high-tech lab environment. The view is framed as if seen through a circular lens, highlighting the intricate details of the circuitry and the thoughtful expression of the man. The background features futuristic digital displays and diagrams, enhancing the scene&#x27;s innovative and technical atmosphere.&quot;
       width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
   An engineer lost in thought, surrounded by a maze of circuits and the glow of futuristic interfaces.
  &lt;&#x2F;figcaption&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been swamped with projects and short on energy to tackle them, partly because of my worsening eyesight. I have glaucoma, but thankfully no loss of vision. My treatment includes twice-yearly eye pressure checks and nightly latanoprost. Even so, my glasses prescription seems to need constant updates, and I’ve always had a lot of floaters. My ophthalmologist reassures me that the floaters and eye pressure are fine, but my vision keeps changing, which is frustrating. After a recent visit to an optometrist for new glasses (an immediate improvement at first), I quickly found myself struggling again. It’s baffling how fast my eyesight shifts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ongoing vision issue is a big reason I’m putting off other projects. Other medical concerns, like my heart health, are actually improving. I have two SunFounder Pis to build, a few minor tasks, and I’m refining my blog and social-event posting software. I expect these projects to be fully functional soon, and I’ll update my blog as they progress.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having plenty to work on, my motivation is flagging.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The Star Trek Computer: My Vision for AI</title>
        <published>2025-10-02T07:35:00-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-10-02T07:35:00-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/the-star-trek-computer-my-vision-for-ai/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/the-star-trek-computer-my-vision-for-ai/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/the-star-trek-computer-my-vision-for-ai/">&lt;figure class=&quot;captioned&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;starship-bridge_robot-orchestra_08.png&quot;
       alt=&quot;A human conductor stands on a podium, baton raised, directing a futuristic orchestra of humanoid robots with glowing blue accents. The robots sit in traditional orchestral formation with violins, cellos, and other instruments. Through the large curved observation window behind them, the saucer section and nacelles of a Federation starship resembling the USS Enterprise are visible against the backdrop of deep space. The walls of the starship interior feature subtle LCARS-style glowing panels.&quot;
       width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    A conductor leads a robotic orchestra aboard a starship, with the USS Enterprise framed through the observation deck windows.
  &lt;&#x2F;figcaption&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer: Personal log, Stardate: Current.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want AI that resembles two distinct concepts, not the general artificial intelligence (AGI) that others are trying to create. I envision AI to be like the &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; computer and helpful robots like Robby the Robot from &lt;em&gt;Forbidden Planet&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or Sonny from &lt;em&gt;I, Robot&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, without any violent programming. I also want a robot companion like the one from &lt;em&gt;Red Planet&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I do not want androids, cyborgs, or anything in between.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have listened to Ed Zitron and read a post from Greg Morris, who think AI systems are merely slop machines and a fad &quot;word salad&quot; generator.&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am having to proactively ask others not to send me AI slop to make my life easier. If I am having to rewrite the shallow nonsense that every LLM produces anyway, I might as well just do it myself from scratch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I believe AI is useful. I am using these services as &lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and you have to look at them that way. I am not a coder, so I use these machines to accomplish what I want. I do not care if the resulting programs are long and &quot;slop,&quot; as long as they perform the intended task and pose no security problems. Modern computers and software can easily handle code that is not perfectly efficient. I believe that within five years, AI will have coding mastered and will be able to fix all the &quot;slop code&quot; it might be producing today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Morris&#x27;s frustration is understandable. He has spent decades building his skills as a designer and communicator, and now he has to deal with people sending him AI-generated &quot;slop&quot; content that he has to rewrite. Ed Zitron raises similar concerns about &quot;slop code,&quot; arguing that AI-generated code is unreliable and that LLMs cannot be trusted to do the same thing every time.&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; Both critiques are valid, particularly when AI outputs are passed off as professional work or sent to professionals who then have to fix them. However, I am not claiming to be a designer or coder, nor am I sending AI-generated work to professionals. I am using AI to build things for myself that I wouldn&#x27;t otherwise be able to create or pay to have created.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shows like &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Aliens&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; all have AI that is very advanced, yet the technology remains in the background rather than replacing humans entirely. They have androids, synthetics, holograms, hyperspace travel, and computers that navigate across galaxies. But computers do not run everything. Humans fly the ships, make the decisions, and win the battles. The computer in &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is the way I see AI eventually being: always accessible, able to perform any task asked of it, capable of writing flawless code, but humans remain at the heart of technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans will be the conductor and the AI will be the orchestra. This is how I want my AI to be for the future: not replacing humans but supporting us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer: End Personal log.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Morris, &lt;em&gt;I Did It Myself&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gregmorris.co.uk&#x2F;2025&#x2F;09&#x2F;24&#x2F;i-did-it-myself.html&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ed Zitron, &lt;em&gt;The Case Against Generative AI&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wheresyoured.at&#x2F;the-case-against-generative-ai&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>My Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy Update</title>
        <published>2025-09-27T16:09:37-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-09-27T16:09:37-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/my-hypertrophic-cardiomyopathy-update/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/my-hypertrophic-cardiomyopathy-update/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/my-hypertrophic-cardiomyopathy-update/">&lt;p&gt;I went to the doctors on Friday, hopefully for the last of the required three ECHOs I need while on my medication called &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.camzyos.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Camzyos&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (you may have seen the commercials on TV for it). I have been on 5mg since June for my Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy, and I am oversimplifying here, but the results have been mixed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the positive side, it has helped significantly. My numbers have definitely improved, not only on my LVOT obstruction (how much oxygenated blood gets out of my heart) but also on my ejection fraction. My shortness of breath during exertion or regular activities is completely gone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are concerning side effects. My fatigue is still there, if not a little worse, and my heart rate is consistently fast with tachycardia episodes. Your heart should slow down during sleep, but mine stays at 75-90 beats per minute or higher all night long, and I can feel it constantly. This is not AFib (an irregular fast heartbeat) but rather a fast, rhythmic beat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doctor reviewed my previous Holter monitor readings and saw the tachycardia episodes and abnormal beats firsthand. He decided I need to be put on Verapamil to address these short runs of tachycardia and the SVT (Supraventricular Tachycardia) and VT (Ventricular Tachycardia) abnormal beats I experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also other news from my cardiac MRI done last week, though they are not sure how to interpret it yet. Both radiologists who read my MRI need to provide clarification on quantifying my heart scarring. The report only stated &quot;diffuse LGE&quot; (Late Gadolinium Enhancement), which on its own is concerning, but they need a specific number to determine if I need an implantable ICD device to prevent sudden episodes of Ventricular Fibrillation (VFib), which anyone who has watched medical shows knows is the reason for Code Blues at hospitals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The treatment protocol is complicated. I cannot start Verapamil immediately because Camzyos has a REMS protocol (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fda.gov&#x2F;drugs&#x2F;drug-safety-and-availability&#x2F;risk-evaluation-and-mitigation-strategies-rems&quot;&gt;Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). Camzyos can cause heart failure if not properly monitored, though this is reversible by stopping the medication. The protocol requires cutting the Camzyos dose in half when starting Verapamil, but my doctors do not want to do that in my case because that reduced dose would probably be ineffective.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, they are increasing my dose to 10mg and monitoring how I respond for two to three weeks with another ECHO (which are painless and no problem to do). Then they will add Verapamil, which will require cutting my Camzyos dose in half, allowing me to benefit from both medications. They must proceed this way because concurrent use of both drugs can potentially lower ejection fraction and cause heart failure, so they have to take it slowly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for my hoped-for six-month reprieve from ECHOs. I now have another one scheduled for next month, plus visits with my cardiologist, the HCM medication specialist cardiologist, and my electrophysiologist. All of these appointments just happen to be converging next month due to their regular yearly or six-month checkup schedules, in addition to this newly added ECHO.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>When Police Lights Stay On: Law Enforcement Cruise Mode</title>
        <published>2025-08-28T11:49:57-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-08-28T11:49:57-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/law-enforcement-cruise-mode/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/law-enforcement-cruise-mode/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/law-enforcement-cruise-mode/">&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;police-cruise-mode-confused-driver-illustration.png&quot; alt=&quot; Illustration of a driver looking confused as a police car follows with steady red and blue lights.&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in Hillsborough County, Florida. Within the last few months, our Hillsborough County Sheriff&#x27;s Office (HCSO) and at least one other local agency have been using what they call &lt;em&gt;cruise mode&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; with their emergency lights. This is creating a lot of confusion for motorists, myself included.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this mode, the emergency lights are steady and static while the deputy drives normally. The problem is you cannot tell if they want you to move over, pull over, or simply let them pass with priority. Traditionally, emergency lights flash, sometimes with sirens, which signals drivers how to respond. The issue is especially acute when a patrol car is directly behind you or approaching an intersection in front of you. I’ve been in both of these situations, and each time I was unsure how to react.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, HCSO received enough questions, complaints, and inquiries that local news media began covering the issue. At least one couple was involved in a serious accident linked to confusion over this policy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tampabay28.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;local-news&#x2F;i-team-investigates&#x2F;cruise-lights-on-hillsborough-county-sheriffs-office-patrol-cars-raise-questions-confusion-among-drivers&quot;&gt;ABC Action News Tampa Bay (WFTS) report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; documents one such accident.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fox13news.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;hcso-deputies-begin-using-cruise-lights-patrol-cars-deter-crime&quot;&gt;FOX 13 Tampa Bay report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; explains the reasoning behind the new lighting mode.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube &quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;SPM-CGaE-BE&quot;
    webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen frameborder=&quot;0&quot;
    &gt;
  &lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One key issue is that HCSO did not widely publicize this change until after they had already begun using it. Nor did they hold any public hearings, request public input, or take comments about this non-statutory change. Florida law is clear about when emergency lights may be used and when emergency vehicles may claim special driving privileges:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;§316.2397(3)(c)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Authorized emergency vehicles may operate emergency lights and sirens in an emergency. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.leg.state.fl.us&#x2F;Statutes&#x2F;index.cfm?App_mode=Display_Statute&amp;amp;URL=0300-0399%2F0316%2FSections%2F0316.2397.html&quot;&gt;Online Sunshine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;§316.072(5)(a)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, a driver of an authorized emergency vehicle may claim special privileges when responding to an emergency call, transporting organs or surgical teams for transplant, pursuing a suspect, or responding to a fire alarm. The driver &lt;strong&gt;“may exercise the privileges set forth in this section, but subject to the conditions herein stated.”&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.leg.state.fl.us&#x2F;Statutes&#x2F;index.cfm?App_mode=Display_Statute&amp;amp;URL=0300-0399%2F0316%2FSections%2F0316.072.html&quot;&gt;Online Sunshine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The privileges in &lt;strong&gt;§316.072(5)(b)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; include parking or standing as needed, carefully proceeding past a red or stop after slowing, exceeding speed limits without endangering life or property, and disregarding movement or turning regulations without endangering life or property. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.leg.state.fl.us&#x2F;Statutes&#x2F;index.cfm?App_mode=Display_Statute&amp;amp;URL=0300-0399%2F0316%2FSections%2F0316.072.html&quot;&gt;Online Sunshine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;§316.072(5)(c)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; requires “due regard for the safety of all persons” and does not protect a driver from reckless disregard. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.leg.state.fl.us&#x2F;Statutes&#x2F;index.cfm?App_mode=Display_Statute&amp;amp;URL=0300-0399%2F0316%2FSections%2F0316.072.html&quot;&gt;Online Sunshine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separately, &lt;strong&gt;§316.126(3)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; says that when an emergency vehicle is en route to an existing emergency, it must warn other traffic by an audible signal or a visible signal using displayed blue or red lights, and otherwise proceed consistent with the traffic laws. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.leg.state.fl.us&#x2F;Statutes&#x2F;index.cfm?App_mode=Display_Statute&amp;amp;URL=0300-0399%2F0316%2FSections%2F0316.126.html&amp;amp;utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot;&gt;Online Sunshine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statute does not appear to authorize steady, non-flashing lights while the vehicle is driving normally. Cruise mode is also not mentioned in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.flhsmv.gov&#x2F;pdf&#x2F;handbooks&#x2F;englishdriverhandbook.pdf&quot;&gt;Florida Driver’s Handbook&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, leaving motorists with no official guidance on how to respond:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emergency Vehicles:
Motorists, bicyclists, and pedestrians must yield the right-of-way to law enforcement vehicles, fire engines, and other emergency vehicles using sirens or flashing lights. Pull over to the closest edge of the roadway immediately and stop until the emergency vehicle has passed. Do not block intersections.&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This confusion is not theoretical. I experienced it first-hand a couple of months ago. A deputy was driving behind me with cruise lights on, and I had no idea if he wanted me to move over or not. He did not try to pass, so I continued driving normally through heavy traffic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example happened just the other morning on the University of South Florida campus. A USF Police vehicle was coming the opposite way with static emergency lights on. It was 6:25 a.m. and still dark, so the lights were especially bright. I had a green turn arrow but hesitated because I did not know if he intended to proceed through the intersection. After three or four seconds, I realized he wasn’t moving, so I made my left turn. Even though I already knew about cruise mode, I was still uncertain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the law only permits these lights to be used in flashing emergency mode and requires officers to obey traffic laws otherwise, then this static always-on mode while on routine patrol does not appear to be supported by statute. It also creates unnecessary confusion, especially in a state with a large elderly population who do not need added uncertainty behind the wheel. In addition, tourists and residents from other parts of Florida where agencies do not use cruise mode face even more confusion. I understand the goal is to deter crime, discourage traffic violations, and increase visibility, but in practice cruise mode is causing more confusion and risk than it prevents.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 84 Official Florida Driver License Handbook as issued by the Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles 2025 Edition&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Summer Gratitude: A&#x2F;C</title>
        <published>2025-08-21T23:16:44-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-08-21T23:16:44-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/ac-summer-blog-post/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/ac-summer-blog-post/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/ac-summer-blog-post/">&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;florida-ac-comfort-man-reading-recliner-flat-vector.png&quot; alt=&quot; Illustration of a man in a recliner reading a tablet; sunlit palm trees outside a large window, mini-split A&#x2F;C on the wall, and an iced tea on a side table.&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, especially in the heart of summer, I’ve been thinking about air conditioning and the inventions I’m most grateful for that have matured over my lifetime. I don’t think I could have lived in Florida back in the day without air conditioning. You really notice it when it’s gone. Last year, after Hurricane Milton, we lost power for four days. I couldn’t sleep, not only because the A&#x2F;C was off but also because my CPAP had no power. That got me thinking about the top five inventions I’m grateful for:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Air conditioning&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Television&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal computer&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indoor bathroom&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick story about number five. My grandmother had a cabin in rural Florida with an outhouse until she brought in a trailer with an indoor bathroom. I hated having to go outside to that outhouse, especially at night. You never knew what might have made its way in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these is pretty self-explanatory, but in Florida I’ve always said the state would be a ghost town without air conditioning. That’s why it’s number one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>I Didn’t Need a Report to Know Tampa Traffic Is Bad</title>
        <published>2025-08-05T22:57:47-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-08-05T22:57:47-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/traffic-in-tampa/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/traffic-in-tampa/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/traffic-in-tampa/">&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;i75-fowler-crash-.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Traffic camera view of I-75 Southbound near Fowler Avenue in Tampa at night, showing heavy congestion in the right lanes with long lines of red brake lights.&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was just watching our local news on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fox13news.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;tampa-ranks-13th-worst-city-us-traffic-consumeraffairs-study&quot;&gt;fox13tampabay.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and they had a story on a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.consumeraffairs.com&#x2F;automotive&#x2F;cities-with-the-worst-traffic.html#methodology&quot;&gt;ConsumerAffairs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; report about which cities have the worst traffic. The city I have to travel to for work (Tampa) was ranked 13th worst in the nation and number 3 in the state, behind Miami and Orlando.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will say I don&#x27;t know much about Miami. I’ve only been there once for a few hours before leaving. Orlando, though, is definitely worse than Tampa. I&#x27;ve lived in the City of Tampa proper and now live in the suburbs, Brandon, and the traffic has always been bad in both places. But over the last couple of years, since everyone returned to the office, it has been the worst I’ve ever seen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only time I saw traffic improve around here was during the early days of the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drive from Brandon to the USF area of Tampa for work. It used to take me about 30 to 35 minutes. Nowadays, no matter what time I leave, it takes me 40 to 45 minutes if I have to be at work at 9 AM. On Mondays, when I have to be there by 6:30 AM, it is manageable and still takes me exactly 30 minutes. I can attest to what the researchers found and say it&#x27;s worse than they make it out to be. The commute times they cite are probably too optimistic. If you get caught behind a crash, good luck.  You could be stuck for an hour or more on the interstate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers found the Tampa driver has an average commute time of 28.3 minutes, which is a 1.1% decrease from last year, but is still higher than the national average (26.9 minutes). Meanwhile, Tampa reported 14.01 fatal car crashes per 100,000 people, which is a 12.8% decrease from last year, but also higher than the national average (11.33).&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes it worse is that I-75 is under construction. I think they are trying to add a lane in both directions. I can&#x27;t say for sure, because it&#x27;s really hard to tell what they’re doing right now. Most of the work is on one bridge over a waterway called the Bypass Canal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m glad I don’t have to drive downtown anymore. I dread having to go that way when I visit Tampa General Hospital for echocardiograms during these first few months on my new heart medication. I would much rather drive to USF Health.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I know is that I’m so glad to get home on the days I have to drive in, and I feel blessed that my job now lets me work remotely three days a week. If I had to go back to driving all five days, I would pull my hair out. The one day I go in early is fine on the way there, and I can tolerate it. But even coming home at 3 PM is a challenge. Wednesdays are tough both ways, and my blood pressure peaks on the drive home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I saw this report, I said to myself, “Yes, I could have told you that.” The real question is, when will Tampa and Hillsborough County stop growing, when will people stop moving here, and when will the state and county finally upgrade the roads — or better yet, &lt;strong&gt;overbuild&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; them for once?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumer Affairs Report – &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.consumeraffairs.com&#x2F;automotive&#x2F;cities-with-the-worst-traffic.html&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.consumeraffairs.com&#x2F;automotive&#x2F;cities-with-the-worst-traffic.html&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#TampaTraffic #CommuterLife #FloridaLiving&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Living with HOCM: A Mid-Year Update</title>
        <published>2025-07-20T20:18:52-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-20T20:18:52-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/living-with-hocm-a-mid-year-update/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/living-with-hocm-a-mid-year-update/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/living-with-hocm-a-mid-year-update/">&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;heart-condition-checkup-ink-illustration.png&quot; alt=&quot;Black-and-white hand-drawn illustration of a doctor’s office, showing a doctor with a stethoscope seated at a desk, attentively listening to a male patient. The office includes a computer, medical supplies, bookshelves, and an anatomical heart chart on the wall, all rendered in detailed pen-and-ink linework with subtle cross-hatching.&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in March, I had my six-month checkup with my cardiologist. I told him I was feeling tired and fatigued all the time, more than usual. I thought it might be the medication. My last echocardiogram in August 2024 had shown some improvement, and my PVCs (premature ventricular contractions) were down. So I figured it was just the burden of the meds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I was taking Metoprolol 100mg ER twice a day and Diltiazem 240mg ER once a day. My heart had been doing okay. The few times I went into AFib, the episodes were short. Sometimes just a minute or two, long enough for me to catch it with my Galaxy Watch 6 Classic or my Kardia device, and then it would stop. These episodes only happened maybe every other month.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the fatigue concerned both my doctor and his resident. They recommended I see a specialist at Tampa General Hospital, which USF Health is now integrated with. I made the appointment and went in on May 30, 2025.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that visit, the specialist said I was a good candidate for a drug I had already been following for a while. It’s called Mavacamten, sold under the brand name Camzyos. It has only been available in the United States for a few years. I started taking it last month. My echocardiogram just before that appointment showed a Valsalva gradient of 100 mmHg. A normal reading is typically below 30 mmHg, and anything above 50 mmHg is considered obstructive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, July 18, I had my first follow-up echocardiogram and visit with the doctor. He asked how I was feeling, and I told him the truth. I don’t really notice much yet, other than my heart rate sometimes being a little fast when I try to sleep. The good news is that my PVCs have almost disappeared.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He reminded me that it may take 8 to 12 weeks to really feel or see significant improvement. This medication is meant to ease the symptoms of my condition, but it is not a cure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also wore a 2-week Holter monitor during this time. It didn’t show anything too concerning for PVCs, but it did catch a significant SVT load. For now, we’re going to keep an eye on it. I have a cardiac MRI scheduled in September to check for any scarring, and we’ll reevaluate then.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He told me the medicine is starting to work. My Valsalva gradient dropped from 100 mmHg to about 50 mmHg, an improvement of nearly 50 percent. That means my body is now receiving better oxygenated blood. That was encouraging. He asked if I was having any side effects. Other than the same fatigue and the faster heart rate at night, I haven’t noticed anything unusual.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He ordered a full prescription. Without a copay card, it would have cost me $250 a month, even with insurance. Thankfully, I have the copay card, so I only pay $10 a month. The actual cost to my employer (we are self-insured) is over $8,000 a month for a 30-day supply. The capsule is just slightly bigger than a grain of rice. Incredible, right? It makes me truly grateful for financial support programs and insurance that help cover treatments for a rare, yet commonly underdiagnosed, genetic heart condition.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the results speak for themselves. A 50 percent improvement is something to be thankful for. I also know that starting a drug like Camzyos is a big step, but right now, I would much rather take a medication that I can stop if needed, with little to no long-term consequences, than face surgery. One option would be alcohol septal ablation. The other, more invasive route, involves literally stopping the heart during open-heart surgery and cutting away the thickened part of the muscle, then hoping my heart restarts normally. That is a path I would prefer to avoid if possible, as both are permanent and the medication is not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Keep Trek Running</title>
        <published>2025-07-16T20:09:07-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-16T20:09:07-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/keep-trek-running/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/keep-trek-running/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/keep-trek-running/">&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;star_trek_constant_exploration.png&quot; alt=&quot;Futuristic starship gliding past a distant planet with nebula clouds in the background, symbolizing Star Trek&#x27;s enduring journey and its vision of an attainable future&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was just watching an old episode of &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Deep Space Nine&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I’ve always been into Star Trek, every series except &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: The Next Generation&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I’m not sure why, but I never fully got into that one. The others: &lt;em&gt;The Original Series&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Deep Space Nine&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Voyager&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Enterprise&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and all the movies (except the &lt;em&gt;Next Generation&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; ones), I loved and eagerly awaited. Whether it was a new film release or the next week’s episode, I was always excited. I never watched &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: The Animated Series&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; either, even though I own it on DVD.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Paramount+&#x2F;CBS introduced new series: &lt;em&gt;Discovery&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Picard&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Strange New Worlds&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Prodigy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Lower Decks&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I enjoyed those too, though I hated waiting a week between episodes. I think Netflix got it right: if a show isn’t airing on linear TV, just drop the whole season at once.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I even writing this post? Because I think they need to keep a Star Trek series running constantly. And if there’s no show currently airing, there should be a movie in development. The Star Trek universe is expansive enough to support both quality and quantity. There are fans who will keep these stories going. For me, Star Trek represents a future that feels more achievable than the world of Star Wars.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe we’re close to living in a Star Trek–inspired society technologically. Politically, we may resemble Star Wars more with wannabe emperors, kings, queens, and dictators everywhere or bubbling under the surface.  Still, I prefer the world of Star Trek, it’s more attainable in terms of its technology and processes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take Star Wars, for example. It’s supposed to be highly advanced, yet some aspects feel oddly underdeveloped. Star Trek isn’t perfect either, but its depiction of artificial intelligence seems closer to where we are today. I think we should take inspiration from how AI is portrayed in Star Trek. &quot;The Computer&quot; is always just a word away—accessible, helpful, and never intrusive or obstructive like some AI experiences today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#StarTrek #TV #SciFi #entertainment&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Capturing the Moon with My Seestar S30</title>
        <published>2025-07-06T13:15:00-04:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-06T13:15:00-04:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/zwo-seestar-s30-post/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/zwo-seestar-s30-post/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/zwo-seestar-s30-post/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted a telescope. Something I could use to take photos and videos of the night sky with my phone or camera. I recently came across a YouTube video about the Zwo Seestar S50, but since this is my first telescope, I decided to start with the more beginner-friendly &lt;strong&gt;S30&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and bought it for my birthday.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve owned it for a couple of months, but only recently started using it seriously. Here are some of the first photos I captured with it on &lt;strong&gt;July 4, 2025&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;seestars3007042025.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moon from Seestar S30&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;seestars3007042025(1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Detailed moon surface from Seestar S30&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These images were taken right from my front yard — I still can’t believe the clarity. Here’s one I took with my phone (Galaxy S24 Ultra, no zoom) while I was setting up the Seestar:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;moonfromphnes24ultranonzoom07042005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moon from phone with no zoom before telescope setup&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that evening, we heard fireworks going off in the distance. While the moon was the star of the night, I also caught this fun fireworks shot from our front yard. We were hearing more fireworks from our neighbors all around us than we were actually seeing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;fireworksathome07042025.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fireworks from home on July 4th&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m planning to set up a dedicated page in the future as I learn more about using the &lt;strong&gt;Seestar S30&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. I hope you enjoyed these photos as much as I enjoyed experimenting with the telescope. It’s truly amazing how it filters out light and zooms in on the moon with such detail.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;#astronomy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#telescopes&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#moon&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#personal&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Blogging My Way: Typora + Git + Cloudflare + Micro.blog</title>
        <published>2025-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Michael Mitchell
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/myfirstpost/"/>
        <id>https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/myfirstpost/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/myfirstpost/">&lt;p&gt;This post serves two purposes. First, it marks the inaugural entry 🥳 on my new blogging system.
I&#x27;m using Typora ✍️ to write and save my posts locally in a folder. From there, I &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; them to my GitHub repo 🔁, which then deploys to Cloudflare Pages 🌐. Finally, the RSS feed is imported into Micro.blog 📰.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not as elegant as MarsEdit 💻—the polished Mac-only tool—but it works for now and lets me keep using Typora, which I really like.
I tried Obsidian 🧩, but it felt too complicated. The whole &quot;vaults&quot; system 🤯 didn’t click with me. Typora is just simple and clean ✅.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;#blogging&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#typora&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
